<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>noegel.io</title><link>https://noegel.io/</link><description>noegel.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 20:02:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noegel.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to make an AC smart</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-11-22-climate-control/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 20:02:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-11-22-climate-control/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a room that - in winter - needs some heating. Instead of connecting it to my central heating system,
I decided to use my mobile AC which can also heat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitoring the flow and return temperature of my heating system</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-04-22-flow-return-temperature-monitor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 18:48:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-04-22-flow-return-temperature-monitor/</guid><description>&lt;p>To better understand the efficiency and behaviour of my old gas heater, I created a simple monitor for flow and return temperatures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lohnt sich die Dämmung der obersten Geschossdecke? - Februar Update</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-03-08-heizwerte2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 18:48:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-03-08-heizwerte2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nach der Analyse des Gasbedarfs der Monate &lt;a href="/posts/2023-01-06-heizwerte" rel="">Oktober-Dezember&lt;/a> erweitere ich die Betrachtung um die Monate Januar und Februar 2023.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrading an Artillery Genius Pro with a spring steel sheet with PEI surface</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-03-08-artillery-pro-magnetic-bed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 18:48:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-03-08-artillery-pro-magnetic-bed/</guid><description>&lt;p>After accidentally ruining the glas bed of my Artillery Genius Pro I decided to install a spring steel sheet with PEI surface.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lohnt sich die Dämmung der obersten Geschossdecke?</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-01-06-heizwerte/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 18:48:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2023-01-06-heizwerte/</guid><description>&lt;p>Im Oktober 2022 habe ich die oberste Geschossdecke meines Walmdach-Bungalows gedämmt. Hier erfahrt ihr, was es gebracht hat - und was es alles so auszuwerten gibt.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Opening my front door with a fingerprint sensor</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-12-07-fingerprint-doorlock/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 21:11:03 +0100</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-12-07-fingerprint-doorlock/</guid><description>In this simple project I want to build a box that allows my children to enter the house with a fingerprint sensor. At the same time this project doubles as a prototype for video doorbell with fingerprint sensor that I might want to build later.
Prerequisites In my case we are owning a Nuki door lock already: So basically a small box on the inside of my front door that turns the door key when told so via Bluetooth.</description></item><item><title>Replace Genius Pro Extruder</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-11-05-replace-genius-pro-extruder/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 11:12:03 +0100</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-11-05-replace-genius-pro-extruder/</guid><description>I broke the hotend of my Genius Pro - and decided to exchange the entire extruder with the &amp;ldquo;all metal&amp;rdquo; one. This is a short overview.
How it started Some month ago I learned about the new arachne perimeter generator. It is now possible to generate wider or thinner perimeter as it is needed. And I wondered: Will this allow me to print (almost) same quality prints with bigger nozzle sizes?</description></item><item><title>Update ESP32 over the air</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-11-01-arduino-auto-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 09:46:37 +0100</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-11-01-arduino-auto-update/</guid><description>Developing Arduino boards is actually easier than one might think. You plug the development board onto your computer&amp;rsquo;s USB, fire up Arduino IDE, and with just a few key strokes and clicks you can upload a first sketch to your development board. But what do you do if you just finished a more complex project and your development board is hard to reach in a door bell, water tank or robot you built?</description></item><item><title>Heizlastberechnung - Teil 3: Eignen sich meine Heizkörper für eine Wärmepumpe?</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-10-29-heizung/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 10:10:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-10-29-heizung/</guid><description>&lt;p>Die Frage &lt;em>Eignet sich mein Altbau eigentlich für eine Wärmepumpe&lt;/em> hat sich vermutlich fast jeder Altbaubesitzer schon gestellt. Im Netz finden sich allerlei Horrorgeschichten von elektrischen Heizpatronen und der angeblichen Notwendigkeit von Fußbodenheizungen. Es gibt zum Glück Möglichkeiten, das Ganze näherungsweise vorab zu bestimmen. Die wollen wir uns im Folgenden anschauen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Heizlastberechnung - Teil 2: U-Wert von Bauteilen ermittelnn</title><link>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-10-29-uwert-ermitteln/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 10:05:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Daniel</author><guid>https://noegel.io/posts/2022-10-29-uwert-ermitteln/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Geht es ums Haus stolpert man immer wieder über den U-Wert: Sätze wie <em>nach EnEV brauchste &rsquo;nen U-Wert von 0,24 aber für KfW müssen es schon 0,2 sein</em> gehören zu den Standardsätzen des stolzen Altbaubesitzers. Hier betrachte ich kurz, was es mit dem U-Wert auf sich hat, wo man relevante Informationen für sein Haus findet - und wie man die Auswirkung einer Dämmung auf den U-Wert seines Hauses berechnen kann.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>